# Alexander Musayev

# Full stack web developer

**Location:** Saint-Petersburg, Russia **GitHub:** <a href="https://github.com/dreikanter">https://github.com/dreikanter</a>

Email: <a href="mailto:alex@musayev.com">alex@musayev.com</a>
LinkedIn: <a href="https://linkedin.com/in/alexmusayev">https://linkedin.com/in/alexmusayev</a>
Detailed CV: <a href="mailto:musayev.com">musayev.com</a>
Languages: Fluent English and native Russian

#### About me

I have 15 years of experience in software development, including 5 years working remotely. Love to build robust and convenient tools that help my clients to save time, reduce business costs and transform complex to simple. As a remote developer, I value transparent communication and workflows. I can work independently or join a team. I have experience in leading a small development team as well.

## Skills and Technologies

Primary languages: Ruby (Rails, dry-rb, Minitest, Sidekiq), JavaScript (React, Redux)

Web: HTML5, CSS3, SASS, Webpack, countless front-end frameworks and libraries

**DB** and NoSQL: PostgreSQL, MySQL, SQLite, Redis, ElasticSearch

Tools: Git (preferred version control), Rubocop, Reek, ESLint, stylelint

Server infrastructure: Linux, Ansible, AWS, Logstash, nginx

# Recent Experience

## 2015–2019: Full stack developer, architect at PassionDig Inc

**Responsibilities:** System design and features development for an educational web service. Customer requirements analysis, specs drafting and implementation planning. Interviewing and onboarding new developers, maintaining dev environment, performing code reviews.

**Achievements:** I've built an MVP version for an in-person educational service from scratch. Implemented geo-location search engine with flexible ranking logic. Created domain-specific web analytics backend for marketing team. Integrated third-party services, including Google Maps, Stripe, PayPal, Twitter, Facebook, helpdesk software with single sign-on capability, etc. Automated provisioning and deployment workflows. Created UI style guide based on custom reusable React component. Improved Rails application performance. Significantly reduced AWS operational costs for a SAAS infrastructure.

1/2 Last update: 2019/06/04

### 2014–2017: **Full stack developer** at UpWork

Participated in multiple projects as a full-stack web developer. My responsibilities included features development and performance optimization for Rails apps, payment services and social API integration, system automation, etc. Got <u>5 stars rating</u> with 100% job success.

#### 2013–2015: **Architect** at Softin.co

Built an application licensing API. Prototyped a project management web service. Performed UX design and art direction for a mobile game project.

### 2012–2013: Senior software developer at Luxoft (Hewlett Packard)

Participated in WebInspect project development, an <a href="OWASP">OWASP</a>-based web app vulnerability scanner. New features implementation, UI i18n, technical documentation, interviewing and onboarding new developers. C#/.NET, WinForms (MVVM), WPF, Microsoft SQL Server.

## Personal projects

Most of my personal projects are open source (<a href="https://github.com/dreikanter">https://github.com/dreikanter</a>). There are tools for system automation, text processing, web content management, Google Chrome extensions, etc. Here are some examples:

**Freefeed Feeder** (<a href="https://frf.im">https://frf.im</a>) — an automated content publishing service built for FreeFeed.net social network. In production since 2017.

**boodka** (<a href="https://github.com/dreikanter/boodka">https://github.com/dreikanter/boodka</a>) — sugar-free personal budget calculator. An experimental project, inspired by the lack of multi-currency support in YNAB.

**public-static** (<a href="https://github.com/dreikanter/public-static">https://github.com/dreikanter/public-static</a>) — a static website builder that I've been using for a personal blog.

#### Education

**M. Sc.** (2004), St. Petersburg State University of Airspace Instrumentation (SUAI) Department of Automatic Control Systems. Specialty: Automatic Control and Information Processing Systems.

**Postgrad** (2008), St. Petersburg Institute for Informatics and Automation of the Russian Academy of Sciences (SPIIRAS). Specialty: Mathematical and Software Support of Computers, Complex Systems, and Networks.

**Multiple certificates** on system analysis, software architecture and UX design. UpWork and Smarterer.com tests on Python, Ruby, Ruby on Rails (master level).

There are more details on my working experience at <u>musayev.com</u>

2/2 Last update: 2019/06/04